BLESSY SAM GEORGE BE, MBA

DATA ANALYST - Monetization and Sales Operation

CRM | Product Pricing | Operation Management | Data Visualization | Data Analysis

Chennai / +91 9500154989 / blessy-sam-george@gmail.com/ / https://www.linkedin.com/ in/blessy-sam-george/

PROFILE SUMMARY

I come with 4 years of professional experience with expertise in Data Analysis and with an ability to solve problems with efficiency. I am known for excellent interpersonal skills with the ability to build strong ties with partners across multiple regions and passionate to work with numbers. My key specialization includes Product Pricing Operation, Data Visualization (Tableau, Power BI), Data Analysis (Excel, SQL, Python) Skills combined with efficiency decision making, driving overall transformation and operational improvements.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst (Operation Portfolio Specialist)

Mar 2023 – Dec 2023

NielsenIQ Pvt Limited, Chennai, India

- Managed and analysed data from various sales and financial tools, identifying key trends and growth opportunities to inform strategic business decisions.
- Developed a deep understanding of product and market segmentation, building expertise in data ecosystems across multiple production units.
- Defined, measured, and visualized key sales KPIs, including target achievement, price performance, order trends, and pipeline development, using advanced data visualization tools.
- Translated business requirements into specifications for implementing reports and dashboards from multiple data sources.
- Collaborated with specialists, leads, and managers to understand reporting requirements and build appropriate solutions.
- Prepared and presented statistical information for internal and external use. Provided technical assistance and cross-training to team members, enhancing overall team capability.

Business Analyst (Pricing) - Monetization & Sales Operations

Mar 2021- Dec 2022

Hotpack Packaging Industry LLC, Dubai, UAE

- Analysing & Interpreting pricing proposal (PRF) approved by Business units and drafting pricing-related communication. Foreign exchange currency setup in Falcon EBS.
- Calculating the percentage of deal discounts for channel distributors across all regions.
- Validating the price books at every stage to publish with accurate data and ensuring the process controls are adhering to the SOX controls. Support internal audit and external SOX audit with PWC.
- Identifying and evaluating gaps in the process and come up with efficient process centric solution to ensure accuracy, completeness and timeliness. Huge data handling and maintenance in tools/system.
- Proactively interacting with sales, deal management, order management, revenue etc. to gather information, resolve product and pricing-related problems, and makes recommendation for process.
- Presentation of pricing analysis, quarterly metrics and upcoming quarterly business requirements to leadership explaining all the win/loss and solution for the same.

Associate Customer Service

Sep 2020 - Mar 2021

Sutherland Global Service, Chennai, India

- Managed customer inquiries, processed payments, and provided exceptional customer service.
- Upsold customers to new products or services, demonstrating strong interpersonal and communication skills.
- Worked collaboratively within a team environment to achieve project goals and deliver high-quality data solutions.

Operation Executive Seiko Denki India Private Limited, Chennai, India

Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

- Oversee and manage all aspects of the manufacturing operations at Master company.
- Created advanced Excel reports, including interactive dashboards, to provide actionable insights to management and clients.
- Collaborate with other departments to coordinate production schedules and meet customer demands.

TOOL SKILLS

Excel (Advanced) | SQL | Tableau | Power BI | Python | Macros | Data Analysis & Reporting | Data Modelling

EDUCATION

Anna University, Coimbatore, India (Full-Time)

July 2018 - Aug 2020

MBA - Operation and Finance Management

Loyola Institute of Technology, Chennai, India (Full-Time)

Jun 2013 - Apr 2017

B.E - Electronics and Communication Engineering

CERTIFICATE

- Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate (Jan 2024 May 2024)
- SQL, Advance Excel Business Analyst and project management collaboration.